# KEIVAN MOKHTARPOUR, MSc

1650 Lincoln Ave. ♦ Montreal, QC H3H 1H1 ♦ 438 722 5044 ♦ m.keivan73@gmail.com ♦ LinkedIn ♦ GitHub ♦ LeetCode SUMMARY

Motivated engineering graduate with more than 5 years of experience in data science, machine learning, and engineering. Excel in dynamic, fast-paced roles, with a strong grasp of teamwork, punctuality and adaptivity. Collaborates and coordinates well with team members, communicating overarching goals, and rectifying operational issues using a problem-solving mindset to ensure timely deliverables.

#### **AREAS OF EXPERTISE**

Project Management Individual & Teamwork Verbal & Written Communication Data Science Cloud Computing Optimization Machine Learning Artificial Intelligence Troubleshooting & Problem Solving

#### **TECHNICAL PROFICIENCIES**

Technical Skill

Python, MATLAB, R, SQL, Linux, Scikit-learn, Tensorflow, Keras, AWS, Docker, Git, Seaborn, Numpy, Scipy, Matplotlib, Pandas, Word, Outlook, Excel Vlookup, Power BI, Latex

#### **ACADEMIC EXPERIENCE**

## Research Assistant, Concordia University

2018 - 2021

## **CONCORDIA UNIVERSITY**

- Performed as a data analyst for the fluidic laboratories of Concordia University.
- Exploited computer vision tools to perform classification tasks in Python and Tensorflow.
- Developed machine learning techniques to shrinkage the data.
- Created technical reports, graphs, tables, and codes using Latex, Power BI, Python and GitHub.

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

• K. Mokhtarpour, M. Jadidi, A. Dolatabadi, **Modal Analysis-Based Classification of Liquid Jets in Crossflow**, Atomization and Sprays Journal, Accepted, 2021.

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Teaching Assistant 2018 – 2019

#### **CONCORDIA UNIVERSITY**

- Organized online and in-person classes and trouble-shooted problems.
- Supervised and trained over 200 bachelor students using leadership skills.
- Applied assessment skills to evaluate assignments and quizzes fairly.

Data Science Intern 2016 – 2018

#### TARAVOSH CONSULTING GROUP

- Imported data from different sources: database queries and etc.
- Predicted system performance using machine learning algorithms for datasets with various levels of completeness.
- Analyzed the past selling trends to predict the future sellouts and help on saving promoting budgets.
- Developed effective visualizations to present findings using tools such as Seaborn, Plotly, Matplotlib, and etc.

## **PROJECTS**

#### **PvSVD**

• A GUI classifier trained on an image class of multiphase fluid flows.

#### **Risk Management**

• Risk level analysis using deep neural networks based on a research paper performed in Tensorflow.

#### **Toronto Coffee House Location Finder**

• A data-driven approach to find the best possible locations for opening up a coffee house in the greater Toronto area.

Continued on next page

# KEIVAN MOKHTARPOUR, MSc

## **CERTIFICATIONS**

## Deep Learning Specialization (Link)

ISSUED BY: DEEPLEARNING, AI



Neural Networks and Deep Learning (ANN)
Improving Deep Neural Networks: Hyperparameter Tuning, Regularization and Optimization
Structuring Machine Learning Projects
Convolutional Neural Networks (CNNs)
Sequence Models (RNN, LSTM, Attention Models, Transformers)

## IBM Data Science Professional Certificate (Link)

**ISSUED BY: IBM** 



Databases and SQL for Data Science Data Analysis Data Visualization Machine Learning

#### **EDUCATION**

## MILA Deep Learning School (Remote) | MONTREAL, QUEBEC

2021

- Relevant courses: CNNs RNNs bias and discrimination in AI
- School organized by well-known researchers: Yoshua Bengio and others

## Master of Science- Mechanical Engineering | CONCORDIA UNIVERSITY, MONTREAL, QUEBEC

2020

- ◆ GPA: 4.08 /4.30
- Thesis: data-driven modelling of multiphase flow systems.
- Excellence entrance award recipient
- Nominee for the best M.Sc student

# Bachelor of Science- Mechanical Engineering | TEHRAN POLYTECHNIC, TEHRAN, IRAN

2016

- ◆ GPA: 3.40 /4.00
- Relevant Coursework: C programming, differential equations, linear algebra, probability, optimization